In the previous sessions we covered the init process and zygote process.
We also looked at the code from their side or the systems are what process?
Let's start from there and see what exactly system server is doing.
So in the previous session we looked at the cigarette in the double, right?
So there we saw that the systems are where these systems are.
A process is created using port mechanism.
So it's down here support system server.
So inside port system server method, we could see that the command line is hardcoded and here we could
see these systems are working class.
It refers to the system server node and Java plus.
And using these arguments.
Here.
It's calling the food system.
So what?
So inside water since I was basically calling it day and night method called system server.
So this you can find within.
This CPB file.
So if you look at, you can see that it's the package name and the class name.
Haitham Dot Android dot internal door toys, not zygote.
So the scientists say God or Java, from which it is called there's this one.
So finally this method will come back to this system.
So all the systems are one main method.
And as you could see from the main method, it simply calls systems that were not run.
So within the run there are three main methods.
So the START Bootstrap Services method, the START Core Services method and START other services method.
The START Bootstrap Services method starts small, tying the all political services that are needed
to get this system off the ground.
These services have complex mutual dependencies, which is why it is initialized at one place.
So in case if you are planning to add a service that is very much interdependent on these bootstrap
services, then you could add within this method.
But if it is not dependent on any of these bootstrapped services, you should not add again, you should
consider adding it in these other mental start core services or start other services.
Okay, so mostly this will be the proper place if you decide with which you are going to add doesn't
have any dependency on these, then it's advisable.
You can add it in the start.
Other services method.
Okay.
So the START Bootstrap Services is responsible to start a set of services which are actually inter-related.
So here is a list of major services which are started by bootstrap services.
So here we have INSTALLER, which is basically a service class used when the system stores the APK and
then we have the activity manager service or Amazon, which is basically responsible for start up switching
and scheduling of these four major components of the system.
Then the power manager serves more power related calculations in the system.
Lights service for managing the back end leads.
Display Manager The Service for handling the display devices within the system.
User Manager Service, Multi User Mode Management, Sensor services, all basically to provide various
sensor services for the system.
And finally, the package manager service for installing uninstalling APIs.
So in this method, you can see it starts each of the services one by one, like the installer we started
here.
Our stats services started here and activity manager.
Our manager, thermal manager and many of the services have started here.
So you can also look at the trace logs.
You could see when it is started and when it is up and running.
So next we have start course services.
So the start or services method starts some essential services that are not dependent on the bootstrap
process.
So here is a list of main services within the core service.
So here we had the battery service which manages just the battery related services.
Usage stats service.
It collects how often users use each app and how often they are used.
Then web webview update service service related to webview a bit.
And then we have the typical service.
It's basically to handle the TPU and the TPU driver.
So we didn't start core services.
As we can see, it starts.
All these services they use each service, the view update service.
And here you can see if the device supports feature debut, then it starts it.
So similarly, there are many conditions across these methods.
So if the device supports a particular feature to start some services and the binder called start service
loop new persistent service and finally the debut service.
So next stop start other services start other services method starts a set of miscellaneous services.
So here is a list of major services started by start of the service method.
So the camera service, this handles the camera later steps, alarm manager service.
It's the global timer management service input management service.
So this is supported.
I mean, the input keyboard.
And then we have the window manager service, that is the window management.
The we are manager service, it's part of the we are more management services, Bluetooth service,
throughput management service, notification manager service and as the notifications of the system.
Device Storage monitor service, so is related to the SD card storage related management services and
the location manager service handles the location stuffs and audio service standards that all audio
related services.
So we look in detail on some of these services in the later sessions.
So there are a few more things which we need to note down here.
Like some of the services are only for some devices and so here you can see is only for s watch.
And then.
And I certainly have some condition.
So if it is disabled cameras, I will then do that.
No, disabled, then do that.
And similarly, there are some cases where it's only for automotive and there are some cases where it's
only for TV.
So this is only called.
So this case, we check if there is a featured wife.
Then early start the wife by and hear evidence they use B feature.
Then start the US B service server as a backup feature, then start that feature, then start the apogee
service.
So there are many conditions here, so not all time.
You set a started for all devices.
So based on the device and some configurations, it will ignore some of the services.
And if you come down at this, we can see that it says to activity manager service that the system is
ready and this tells the activity manager that it's okay to run the third party code.
So this is an example where it checks for feature automotive.
So these will get started only if the build is an automotive build.
And at this point, you basically start the system.
So this method is responsible for starting the system.
We will dig deeper into this in week out of the system.
You might start a process.
So this is basically the last service.
Within the start, other services method.